# **Eric Constantinides**

eric@ericconstantinides.com San Jose, CA

https://github.com/ericconstantinides

in https://linkedin.com/in/constantinides



#### Intro

In a nutshell: I'm a passionate UI Architect specializing in JavaScript, React, CSS, and Vanilla JS. Most importantly, I always strive for an Amazing User Experience!

Most Recently: I'm a UI Architect at Automation Anywhere working on the Automation 360 platform using React and JavaScript.

**Previously:** I was working on the Automation Anywhere Developer Portal, a React / Next.js web app and the Automation Anywhere Bot Store. **Before that** I was a UI Engineer a Insureon in San Jose, Ca.

## Experience

#### Automation Anywhere Robotic Process Automation (RPA) Provider in San Jose, CA

Apr 2019 - Current

UI Architect (Dec 2020 - Current): UI Architect, Automation 360 Platform

Lead UI Engineer (July 2019 - Dec 2020): Lead UI / Front-End Engineer on Bot Store, Private Bot Store, and Developer Portal

Senior UI Engineer (Apr 2019 - July 2019): Senior UI / Front-End Engineer on Bot Store and Private Bot Store

- Automation 360 (2021-Current) UI Architect, React, CSS Modules, JS, CSS
- Developer Portal (2020) Lead UI / JavaScript / React Engineer, Next.js, React, CSS Modules, JS, CSS, Wordpress
- Private Bot Store (2019-2020) Lead UI / JavaScript / React Engineer, React, Webpack, CSS Modules, Post CSS, JS, CSS, Wordpress
- Bot Store (2019-Current) Lead UI / JavaScript / React Engineer, React, Webpack, CSS Modules, Post CSS, JS, CSS, Wordpress

#### Insureon Online Business Insurance Broker in Campbell, CA

Jan 2018 - Apr 2019

Senior UI & Front-End Engineer: Co-engineer for building the Customer Portal for Insureon. Customer Portal is built using React, Webpack, CSS Modules, Post-CSS, Babel, React Router, etc. Responsible for building out app pages using CSS and JS. In addition, my authored initiatives include:

- JSON Forms framework for Object-based form prototyping
- Intelligent Form Validation cascading rule-based validation with minimally intrusive user errors
- Features Higher-Order-Component control UI features in the console including HMR
- Create-Menu build responsive HTML menus from JSON objects
- Progressive Web App PWA implementation including Manifest and smart-caching using Service Workers
- Global CSS variables in JS CSS variables accessible in both JS and CSS with hot-module-replacement
- withAnalytics Higher-Order-Component Google Analytics wrapper for intelligently triggering analytic events
- withAnimation Higher-Order-Component tiny wrapper to add CSS animation props to any component
- Tiny Datepicker Component 90% smaller DatePicker with no dependencies on Moment.js

### BottomlessBrunch.com in San Jose, CA

Apr 2017 - Jan 2018

**Full-Stack UI Engineer:** Developed bottomlessbrunch.com, a React and Redux responsive web-app which graphically renders "bottomless" brunch locations in the United States. Integrated Google Maps, Google Places, and YELP APIs. Created administration back-end which combines multiple APIs to create new locations in seconds. Served on an AWS Server through an NGINX proxy with a Node/Express API.

#### EverSport Media Online Video Provider in Los Gatos, CA

Sep 2015 - Jan 2017

Lead Front-end Developer: Lead Front-end Developer for Eversport's themes and modules using JavaScript, SCSS / CSS, Drupal and PHP. Designed and developed the site and the user-interface for the Single Page App media player that ran on 3rd party sites.

 EverSport.tv (2015-2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal, PHP, JS, CSS  Single Page App (2015-2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, JS, CSS, JSON, AJAX Senior Web Developer (Jan 2014 - June 2015): Orchestrated the weekly developer meetings; drafted timelines and estimates for future projects; composed technical briefs for client-side contracts; lead web development projects.

Web Developer (Jan 2012 - Jan 2014): Architected content structure for websites. Hand-coded HTML, SCSS (CSS), and JS from designs into responsive and interactive pages. Implemented JavaScript libraries and wrote custom JavaScript/jQuery code.

- PureStorage.com (2015) Lead Developer, WordPress, JS, CSS
- Adallom.com (2015) Lead Developer, WordPress, JS, CSS
- Platfora.com (2014) Lead Developer, WordPress, JS, CSS
- Alteryx.com (2014) Lead Developer, Drupal, JS, CSS
- Okta.com (2014) Lead Developer, WordPress, PHP, JS, CSS
- Abaxis.com/veterinary (2013) Lead Developer, WordPress, JS, CSS
- SocialChorus.com (2013) Lead Developer, WordPress, JS, CSS
- Pentaho.com (2013) Lead Developer, Drupal, JS, CSS
- LiveOps.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal, JS, CSS
- IslandResortAndCasino.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal, JS, CSS

### Independent Web Developer in San Jose, CA

2005 - Current

Full MERN Stack Web-App Developer. Previously, Full LAMP Stack Developer:

- MineSweeper (2017) Developer / Designer, React, Redux, JS, CSS
- MuddlingThroughCode.com (2017) Developer / Designer, Node, Express, JS, CSS
- EricConstantinides.com (2017) Developer / Designer, React, JSON, Next Is
- ConstantlyBeing.com (2017) Lead Developer, Designer, Drupal, JS, CSS
- Annachich.com (2016) Lead Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal, Drupal Commerce, JS, CSS
- PaoloShoes.com (2015) Lead Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal, UberCart, JS, CSS

- CameronVailDesign.com (2016) Lead Developer, Drupal, JS, CSS
- DukeDuchess.com (2011) Lead Developer, Drupal, Ubercart, JS, CSS
- Bike To Work Day: YouCanBikeThere.com (2008, 2009, 2010, 2011) Lead Developer, Drupal
- BottomlessBrunch.com (2011) Lead Developer, Drupal, CSS
- ChicFashionWeekSF.com (2010) Lead Developer, Drupal, CSS
- BayAreaBikes.org (2008) Lead Developer | Lead Designer, Drupal, CSS

#### Skills

### Primary Skills My main area of concentration

- React, JSX, Redux, NextJs
- JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, ES2015 / ES6, ES2016, lodash
- Testing, Jest, Enzyme
- Node, Express, mongoDB, npm / yarn
- JS Tools, Gulp, Webpack, Babel

- CSS, Sass/SCSS, BEM CSS, FlexBox
- HTML, HTML5
- Git, GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree
- User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), Responsive Web Design (RWD)

#### Supplementary Skills Important proficiencies that aren't my primary focus

- Design Apps, PhotoShop, Illustrator
- Front-end helpers, jQuery, Bootstrap
- PHP, SQL, MySQL
- CMS Theming, Drupal (advanced), WordPress
- Online Tools, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Jira
- Marketing Automation, Eloqua, Salesforce, Marketo
- Cloud Hosting, Acquia, Amazon Web Services, DigitalOcean VPS
- Code Editing, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, Chrome Developer Tools
- Apache, Unix, HTTPS/SSL

### Education

### W.P. Carey School of Business in Tempe, AZ

Arizona State University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems (CIS): 3.75 Computer Information Systems GPA Bachelor of Science, Marketing: 4.0 Marketing GPA